# **Rob Strasser**

## Software Engineer

robstrasserdev@gmail.com • (925) 549-1803 • https://robstrass.github.io/

### CAREER SUMMARY

Experience 2 years as a Software Engineer with startups & a global insurance company

Languages TypeScript/JavaScript, React, Express, NodeJs, GraphQL, ReactNative, Redux, Python, Flask

Tools PostgreSQL, Jest, auth0, Git, JIRA, NSX, MaterialUI, Docker, Figma, AWS S3

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**BoomNation** 

Remote (Birmingham, AL)

Software Engineer 1

11/2023-02/2024

Technologies: Javascript, React, React Native, Node.js, GraphQL, Express, PostgreSQL, Jest, Figma, StoryBook

- Part of a 3 person engineering team that collaborated closely with Product, Marketing, and C-Suite to plan and deliver product features and updates on a consumer-facing app with over 250,000 users in an Agile setting
- Refactored payment pipeline for self-checkout to integrate new pricing models and tier features table leading to a 19% increase in client acquisition
- Built a new mobile login flow resulting in a 25% increase in user signups and a 40% increase in user profile completions by converting a multi-step process into a single-page long-form
- Maintained 100% test coverage on all new code and increased test coverage on legacy code by 10%
- Laid off as part of the reduction of staff due to lack of a successful funding round

Munich Re

Remote (London, UK)

Software Engineer 1, Network Automation (Contract)

02/2023 - 11/2023

Technologies: TypeScript, JavaScript, CosmosDB, Azure DevOps, NSX, vRealize, Postman, Python

- Part of a 5 person team in a contract role delivering internal tooling to facilitate Network Automation
  workflows, serving 40,000+ employees, releasing weekly or bimonthly updates in a CI/CD cycle on a codebase
  with over 113,000 lines of code
- Built a workflow leveraging multiple APIs to automate the process of cleaning the database, NSX
  environments, and vCenters of network segments and virtual machines, reducing manual efforts from 1-3 days
  to 1-hour maximum
- Patched, tested, and re-developed 12+ automation workflows delivered in a non-functioning state by an
  external team, identifying dozens of critical bugs that would have brought down Production or left internal
  applications vulnerable
- Collaborated with 20+ people from 3 different teams spread across Europe, overcoming time differences of 8-10 hours, to achieve project goals by identifying key decision-makers within the organization
- Performed code reviews for 5+ team members on at least a weekly basis, ensuring strict code standards and company policies were met while also personally accounting for 2-4 items per release
- Contract ended due to EOY budget constraints

SPJ Solutions

Remote (Sacramento, CA)

04/2022 - 01/2023

Software Engineer 1

Technologies: Typescript, React, Redux, Express, Node.js, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, NSX, Postman

- Part of a 15+ person Agile team building an application that managed the network virtualization of clients, facilitating the migration of 5000+ virtual machines, serving 100+ clients
- Appointed sole developer of large micro-segmentation feature that took a snapshot of clients' existing network environment's firewall, organizing and deploying migration in 8 steps to the latest version of NSX
- Developed an algorithm to sort and order 4,000+ firewall rules decreasing manual organization by 90%
- Laid off as 1 of 10 employees following company restructuring

2017-2021: Asset Protection Supervisor, team of 8 employees. SDR, met 120% of quota. Learned client leadership & time management

### **EDUCATION & ACCREDITATIONS**

App Academy Coding Bootcamp

07/2021 - 01/2022

CSU East Bay - BS Criminal Justice

09/2013-06/2017